londoninternational.ac.uk 2017-11-01

# Privacy policy & Cookies | University of London International Programmes

The University of London International Programmes recognises that data protection and privacy are an important issue, particularly with regard to the World Wide Web; consequently we take your personal privacy very seriously. The Privacy Policy gives an overview of what information is collected when you access our website and how certain information might be used. Please

We adhere to the principle of data protection and privacy and endeavour to implement it within the guidance of current legislation. Read more on University's data protection policy.

###  Accessing the University of London International Programmes website

As a general rule, the University of London International Programmes website employs the notion of 'public access' and does not require you to login. Consequently, when you access the website you are not required to submit any personal information; however, in common with most website's, certain anonymous data is gathered (via cookies [see below]). For each visitor, our web server collects usage data; similarly, we use certain analytics systems to provide additional anonymised statistics (see information about cookies below) - the type of information obtained might include: the number of page visits per week, the average number of pages viewed by users, domain names (e.g. .com, .ac.uk, .net), referring sites (e.g. Google.com, Yahoo.com), Browser summaries (e.g. the number of visitors using Microsoft Internet Explorer or Firefox) and Operating System reports (e.g. the number of page requests made using Windows XP, Windows 7, [Mac] OS Xx or Unix).

On occasion summary statistics may be disclosed to third-parties, however, it is important to understand that the data doesn't provide any personal information (e.g. email addresses) and isn't attributed to individuals. The primary purpose for collecting the information, which is used on an aggregate basis, is to improve the content and functionality of our website.

In addition to website analytics, we also collect data to deliver targeted advertising based on your use of the site, and to attribute actions taken on the site back to engagement with the University's advertising across the web. This data does not include any personally identifiable information, but may include information such as whether you view a particular web page, which tools or multimedia content you interact with on the site, and whether or not you make an enquiry or application (but strictly not any of the personal details you enter). This data may be shared with our agency partners who run digital advertising on behalf of the University.

***Note:** This data is protected from public access and can only be viewed and disclosed by authorised personnel.

###  Cookies

Cookies are small data structures used by a website to 'request' information from a client (usually a web browser), return the information to the website and then store the information; cookie requests can be enabled and disabled by users. They are not computer programmes and cannot be used to disseminate viruses or access a computer’s hard drive.

There are various instances where the University of London International Programmes website(s) uses cookies, e.g. for website analytics (see above), and other instances where it requires the use of cookies for functionality and authentication purposes, e.g. in the online application process and for access to the student portal.

We also use cookies to deliver targeted advertising based on your use of our site and to measure the performance of our advertising. Information about this and your options for opting out of advertising cookies is available from the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/). Alternatively, consult the documentation for your web browser or mobile device for further options to control which cookies you allow. Advertising technologies which may set cookies on this site include (but are not limited to) AdWords, DoubleClick, and social media platforms (including Facebook, Twitter, and others).

If you have access to the student portal and/or a VLE, then please read the statements relevant to these systems on the portal or VLE.

**How to control and delete cookies**

You may wish to delete or block certain cookies,  how to do this will depend on which web browser you are using;  please consult your web browser user guide for instructions.

###  Web Forms

Where Web Forms are utilised on the site user's are usually required to supply some sort of personal information; this might only be a reply email address, however, elsewhere considerably more detailed information may be required, e.g. in the Online Application process. In general, forms on the University of London International Programmes's website will either contain an explanation about how the information you supply will be used or will provide a link to this page (Data Protection - see below)

###  Data Protection

The information you provide to the University of London International Programmes will be processed in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act (1998) and any other relevant legislation. This data may be used to provide you with further information about relevant services. It may be held on a mailing list or database for this purpose, unless you object (by notifying the University in writing); and it may also be passed on to a third-party (a 'data processor') with whom the University has formally contracted to process your data for this purpose, subject to the safeguards concerning privacy and security of data set out in the Act.

###  Student / social Network(s)

In certain instances the University of London International Programmes's website facilitates communication between students (and staff) via online networks. The networks primarily operate on an 'opt-in' basis, i.e. you have to request that your details are added to the network and consent to their inclusion. It should be noted, however, that staff at the University of London International Programmes don't generally monitor such services, and consequently, the University of London International Programmes doesn't accept responsibility for any information or other material transmitted using a particular service. Similarly, The views expressed by students using these networks (or similar) do not reflect the views of the University of London International Programmes.

If you have access to the Student Portal and/or a VLE, then please read the statements relevant to these systems.

###  Third-Party Links and information

The University of London International Programmes website has links to third-party websites and information. While links and information are only added if they are deemed to be of relevance to our website users, the University of London International Programmes does not accept responsibility for their content.
